a few years ago I felt like I was stuck
in a rut so I decided to follow in the
footsteps of the great American philosopher Morgan Spurlock and trying
something new for thirty days
The idea is actually pretty simple
Think about something you've always wanted to add to your
life and try it for the next thirty days
It turns out thirty days is just about the right
amount of time to add a new habit or subtract
a habit like watching the news from your life
There's a few things that I learned while doing these
thirty day challenges
The first was instead of the months flying by for
gotten
The time was much more memorable
This was part of a challenge I did to take
a picture every day for a month and I remember
exactly where I was and what I was doing that
day
I also noticed that as I started to do Mohr
and harder thirty day challenges my self confidence grew
I went from desk dwelling computer nerd to the kind
of guy who bikes to work for fun
Even last year I ended up hiking up Mount Kilimanjaro
the highest mountain in Africa
I would never have been that adventurous before I started
my thirty day challenges
I also figured out that if you really want something
badly enough you can do anything for thirty days
Have you ever wanted to write a novel Every November
tens of thousands of people try to write their own
fifty thousand word novel from scratch in thirty days
It turns out all you have to do is write
sixteen hundred and sixty seven words a day for a
month
So I did
By the way the secret is not to go to
sleep until you've written your words for the day
You might be sleep deprived but you'LL finish your novel
Now
Is my book the next great American novel No I
wrote it in a month
It's awful but for the rest of my life if
I meet John Hodgman at a Ted party I don't
have to say I'm a computer scientist
No no
If I want to I can say I'm a novelist
So here's one last thing I'd like to mention
I learned that when I made small sustainable changes things
I could keep doing there were more likely to stick
There's nothing wrong with big crazy challenges
In fact there are a ton of fun but they're
less likely to stick
When I gave up sugar for thirty days Day thirty
one looked like this
So here's my question to you
What are you waiting for I guarantee you the next
thirty days are going to pass whether you like it
or not
So why not think about something you have always wanted
to try and give it a shot for the next
thirty days Thanks